# **Archit Vishnoi**

Portfolio: https://v-archit.github.io

Mobile: +1 (585) 553 - 6637 | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/archit-vishnoi | Email: av1567@rit.edu

# Summary

M.S. Game Design Development student with 3 years' experience in Unity Application Development with C#. Extensive work on VR and AR platform using SteamVR, Vuforia, and ARCore. Interested in Gameplay, AI, and Graphics Programming. Seeking to leverage this experience and skills gained to contribute to a Full-time position / Internship for Summer '23. Talk to me about Valorant, Firewatch, Thief 2, and Left4Dead2.

#### Education

# M.S. Game Design Development (3.8/4.0 GPA)

(Aug 2021 - May 2023)

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

• Key coursework: Game Development Process, Engine and Graphics Programming, and Al.

B.Tech. Computer Science Engineering (7.2/10.0 CGPA)

(Aug 2014 – May 2018)

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida

# **Experience**

#### Vizara Technologies Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

(May 2019 - Jun 2021)

Computer Graphics Engineer

- Worked on Unity with C# scripting, Visual Studio, .NET framework, Room-scale tracking with SteamVR, Image/Model Recognition AR apps using Vuforia, and Google ARCore.
- Represented Vizara in India International Science Fest '18 and Unity Dev Conference '19.

# Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

(Aug 2018 – Apr 2019)

Junior Research Fellow

• Worked as Unity Developer on the project, 'Digital Mini Spectacle', goal was to create digital installations using 3D laser scan data, AR, Holographic Projections, with special attention to novelty and optimization using VR, AR, and MR solutions

# **Projects**

#### Into The Babyverse – 3D Space Shooter Game – Unreal C++

(M.S. 4th Sem)

6 DOF spaceship movement, custom hit-planet physics, Chaos destruction, Al

#### Hoodwink (Group) - 3D Wild West Action Game - Unreal C++

(M.S. 3<sup>rd</sup> Sem)

- Responsible for Townsfolk AI with Patrol, Chase, Melee, and Flee behaviors.
- Behavior Trees, BT Tasks, Decorators, Audio-Visual-Touch Perception Graph

#### The AI Story (Group) – 2D Narrative Game – Unity C# Inky

(M.S. 3<sup>rd</sup> Sem)

• Responsible for programming, UI, game logic, Inky file management, dialogue system

## Smoke Particle System - DirectX HLSL DirectXMath ImGUI

(M.S. 3<sup>rd</sup> Sem)

• Custom graphics pipeline for basic particles – size, color, velocity, lifetime, recycle pool

## Infinite Stars - 2D Game - OpenGL GLFW GLEW GLM ImGUI

(M.S. 2<sup>nd</sup> Sem)

Custom graphics pipeline, collision detection, gravity sim, play/pause state, camera movement

# Season Soiree (Group) - 2D Platformer - Unity C#

(M.S. 2<sup>nd</sup> Sem)

• Responsible for UI Design, Animations, and Transitions - VFX using Particle System

# Tower Defense – 2D Strategy Game – Unity C#

(M.S. 1<sup>st</sup> Sem)

• Goal Oriented Action Planning AI - manage economy, spawn/kill combat, siege, labour units

#### Food Delivery - 2D Simulation AI - Unity C#

(M.S. 1st Sem)

• Goal Oriented Action Planning AI – inventory, re-stocking, cooking, delivery, best option

#### **Skills**

- Technical skills:
  - 2+ Years Unity, C#, C++, Data Structures, 3D Mathematics
  - 1+ Years Unreal, OpenGL, DirectX, HLSL
- Soft skills:

Interpersonal Communication, Problem-solving, Detail-oriented, Team player, Critical thinking

#### **Extracurricular Activities**

- Head Coordinator Graphics and Animation Hub, JIIT Noida
- (Aug 2016 May 2018)
- o Organized the Game Development Hackathon in Cybersrishti 2017 College Tech Fest.
- o Organized Unity Game Development and Photoshop Workshop in JIIT Noida in 2018.